あっ もしかして！
Could it be?
サクラちゃん 誤解だってばよ…。
Sakura, you've got it all wrong.
のぞきなんて してねえってばよ！
I'm not peeking!
((ナルト～ッ！
Naruto!
ああ…。
(だから あれほど言ったのに…))
And here I told you not to...
not to...not to...
Oww!
痛い痛い！
許して サクラちゃん…。
Forgive me...Sakura.
サクラちゃん… たぁ～っ！
Sakura...!
Is it morning already...?
もう 朝か。
なんか 寝た気がしねえってばよ。
I don't...feel like I slept at all...
アイツ もう起きたのか…。
Did he get up already...?
ん？
《ねえ！
His stuff...
サイの荷物がねえ！
Sai's stuff is gone...
アイツ どこに行ったんだ!?》
Where...did he go?!
おはよう ナルト君。
ヤマト隊長！
Morning, Naruto.
C-Captain Yamato...
あの野郎が…
あぁ サイの野郎が…！
That jerk, that jerk Sai...
Sai's outside.
サイなら外だ。
あ？
ちょうどよかった。
キミに頼みたいことがあるんだが…。
Your timing's perfect. I've got something
I want to ask you to do for me...
Untitled
(サクラ)へぇ～。
Wow...
絵なんか描くんだ。
So you draw.
何か用ですか？
Is there something you want?
口は悪いくせに
繊細なところもあるのね。
You're foul-mouthed,
but you've also got a sensitive side, huh?
フフッ 意外。
That's a surprise.
その作り笑い➡
That fake smile...
So you're still not through hitting me, huh?
まだ 殴り足りなかったんですか？
ボクのこと。
ちょっとね。
Not quite...
(サクラ)冗談！
ちょっと絵を見にきただけ。
I'm kidding!
I just came to check out your picture.
I was wondering what you were drawing.
(サクラ)どんなもんかと思ってね。
(サイ)そう…。
I see...
こんなところで描いてるから
風景画だと思ってたら➡
At first, I thought you were drawing
a landscape
since you're drawing out here...
これ抽象画ね。
But it's an abstract, huh?
(サクラ)この絵
タイトルは なんていうの？
What's the title of this drawing?
まだ 決めてない？
You haven't decided on one yet?
さぁ？
I don't know.
You don't know...?
さぁ？ って
この絵のタイトルよ 題名！
The name of this drawing, a title.
(サクラ)なんか 考えてるんでしょ。
笑ったりしないから教えて。
You've got something in mind, don't you?
I won't laugh, so tell me.
そんなものないよ。
(サクラ)え？
I've got nothing like that.
What?!
I've drawn tens of thousands
of pictures...
(サイ)今まで 何千何万と
描いてきたけど➡
タイトルなんて つけたことないよ。
but I've never given one a title.
(サイ)だから この絵にも…。
So this doesn't have one, either...
Really?
ふ～ん…。
(サクラ)でも 絵には
普通 題名をつけるものでしょ？
But you're supposed to give
a title to a picture, right?
If it's a portrait,
you give it the name of the person...
肖像画だと
その人の名前とか➡
それ以外の絵でも
そのときの状況や➡
Or with other pictures,
you use the situation,
your feelings or emotions at the time...
自分の気持とか 感情とか…。
To be exact, I couldn't title
one of my drawings even if I wanted to...
正確には タイトルをつけようとしても
つけられないんだ。
(サイ)何も思い浮かばない
何も感じないんだよ。
Nothing comes to mind.
I don't...feel anything.
(サイ)何も…。
Nothing...
どおりで だから無神経なこと
ばっかり言えるんだな。
No wonder you can only say
such callous things!
そろそろ出発だってばよ！
It's about time for us to leave!
ヤマト隊長が呼んでこいってさ。
Captain Yamato told me
to come get you.
(サクラ)うん。
Right.
ふんっ！ こんな絵
たいしたことねえってばよ！
This drawing's nothing special!
そうですね。
You're right...
Just like your "equipment."
キミのチンチンと同じですよ。
カッ！ うぅ… 正直に
はっきり言う…➡
I'm going to be straight with you!
I can't stand you!
オレは テメエが嫌いだ！
If you've got a problem,
文句あんなら
作り笑いなんかしてねえで➡
stop the fake smiles
and tell me straight to my face!
正直に はっきり言いやがれ！
I'll take you on anytime
you want to fight!
ケンカなら いつでも買ってやる！
おっ！ やるってのか？
Oh... You want to fight?!
(サイ)文句…。
I've got...
そんなものないよ。
え？
no problem with you.
I don't care about you at all.
(サイ)キミのことなんて
ホントに なんとも思ってない。
Please go on ahead.
先に行っててください。
ボクも片したら すぐに行きます。
I'll catch up once I've tidied up.
I'll help.
手伝うわ。
(サクラ)これ 印刷じゃないわね。
これも あなたが描いたの？
This...isn't printed.
Did you draw this, too?
Yes.
(サイ)あぁ。
へぇ～ 絵本か。
Wow, it's a picture book, huh?
That looks cool.
(サクラ)おもしろそう！
ふんっ！
Oh! Say...
(サクラ)あ あのさ それ 行く途中に
見せてもらってもいい？
can I take a look
at it along the way?
それは ダメだよ。
これ まだ完成してないから。
I can't let you see it.
It's not finished yet...
それに 人には
渡さないことにしてるんだ。
And I don't hand this over to people.
This is my older brother's book, so...
(サイ)これは 兄さんのだからね。
《自分で描いたって
言ってたのに…》
But he said he drew it himself...
What's he talking about?
《コイツ なに言ってんだ？》
(女将)おおきに またおいでやす。
Thank you... Please come again...
みんな 親睦は深まったかな？
So has your rapport improved?
アハ アハハ！
なんで こんなヤツと！
Why do we have to be with this guy?
やっぱり 恐怖による支配のほうが
よかったかな？
So would you have preferred
control by fear?
大丈夫！ ちゃんと
親睦 深まったってばよ！ ハハハ…。
I-It's okay. Our rapport has improved!
楽しそうですね ナルト君。
何 言ってんの！
Naruto looks like he's enjoying himself...
What're you talking about?
(サクラ)どう見ても
作り笑いじゃない！
That's a fake smile
any way you look at it.
Really?
(サイ)そうなんですか？
You yourself said that
a smile is the best way
厄介ごとをやりすごすには
笑顔がいちばん！
to get through a tough situation, right?
あなた 自分で言ってたでしょ？
そうでしたね。
Oh yeah.
ハハハハハ…。
うん。
((何も感じないんだよ。
I don't feel anything.
I don't care about you at all.
(キミのことなんて
ホントに なんとも思ってない))
(ヤマト)そろそろかな。
It's just about time.
どうしたんです？ ヤマト隊長。
What is it, Captain Yamato?
(ヤマト)こっちだ。
えっ？
This way.
Huh?
(ヤマト)早く。
あぁ わかったってばよ。
Hurry up!
O-Okay!
なんで
わざわざ こんなところを…。
Why are we going to the trouble
of coming through here...?
ギャーッ!!
Captain Yamato!
What's the meaning of this?!
(サクラ)ヤマト隊長！
どういうことですか？
I think the path we were on
was the right way.
もとの道で
合ってると思いますけど。 隊長！
Captain!
I'm sure Lady Tsunade has told you.
綱手様が言ったはずだよ。
それって 何の話だ？
What're you talking about?
(ヤマト)サクラが得た情報は
ワナかもしれないって話だ。
The information Sakura
got might be a trap.
There's a possibility that
the Akatsuki might be...
(ヤマト)いざ 天地橋に着いてみたら
暁が待ち伏せしてる…。
その可能性もあるということだ。
waiting to ambush us
at the Tenchi Bridge.
ナルト君 キミを狙ってね。
They might be after you, Naruto.
No way...
まさか…。
可能性は低いと思うけど
用心に こしたことはないからね。
I don't think there's a great possibility,
but you can never be too careful.
(ヤマト)ここから 天地橋までは➡
We'll proceed along a covert route
as much as possible
できるだけ
人目につかないルートを進むからね。
until we reach the Tenchi Bridge.
Right, got it.
あぁ！ わかったってばよ。
このあたりで いいかな？
I guess this spot is okay.
Huh?
えっ？
まさか…。
Don't tell me...
今夜は ここで休むよ。
えぇ～っ!?
We'll rest here tonight.
What?!
いや 野宿すんなら
こんなだだっ広い所じゃなくて➡
If we're going to camp out,
we should use the cave we just passed by
instead of this wide open area...
さっき 通り過ぎた所に
洞窟があって…。
Step back, everyone.
みんな 少し離れてて。
木遁 四柱家の術！
Wood Style: Four Pillar House Jutsu!
(ヤマト)今日は ここで野宿だね。
We'll camp out here tonight.
こういうのって
野宿って いわないんじゃない？
I don't think you can call something
like this camping out.
おぉ～。
すご～い！
This is amazing...
へぇ～ 中は こうなってんのか。
(サクラ)結構 広いのね。
Wow, so this is what it looks
like on the inside.
It's quite spacious, isn't it?
こりゃあ 部屋のほうも
期待できるってばよ。
I think our room just might
hold some promise.
ん？ あそこだ！
Welcome
Team Kakashi
Over there...
あれ？
(サクラ)意外に 中は殺風景ね。
Huh?
It's surprisingly bare, isn't it?
まぁ 野宿よりは マシだってばよ。
そうね。
W-Well, it's better than sleeping outside.
You're right.
ふぁ～ ひと休み ひと休み。
Break time, break time!
これで 風呂でもあれば…。
Now if only we had a bath, too.
何か用ですか？
Is there something you want?
フン！
何でもねえ。
Nothing at all!
はぁ…。
(ヤマト)みんな 少し集まってくれ。
Gather around, everyone.
それと サクラ
キミに聞いておきたいことがある。
And I want to ask
you something, Sakura.
What is it?
なんですか？
It's about the Akatsuki's Sasori.
暁のサソリについてだよ。
サソリ…。
Sasori...
(ヤマト)
早く聞いておきたかったけど➡
I wanted to ask you sooner,
昨日は そういう話はしないって
約束だったからね。
but I promised that we weren't going to
talk about stuff like that yesterday.
今日は
ゆっくり話してもらうよ。
I want you to tell me everything today...
目の前でサソリを見たのは
キミだけだったからね。
You're the only one who's ever
seen Sasori in person, after all...
はい。
Yes, sir.
(ヤマト)砂隠れから サソリのファイルは
一応受け取ったけど➡
For the time being,
I've received a file on Sasori
from the Hidden Sand...
ヤツの性格や言動
仕草や癖なんかがあったら➡
But tell me in as much detail
as you can
about his personality, behavior,
mannerisms and habits if he has any.
なるべく詳しく教えてくれ。
どういうことだってばよ。
What's this about?
大蛇丸の中に入り込んでるスパイは➡
The spy who's infiltrated
Orochimaru's organization thinks
Sasori is going to meet him
at the Tenchi Bridge.
天地橋に サソリが来ると
思っている。
(ヤマト)すぐに
見抜かれるかもしれないが➡
They might see us through immediately,
サソリに変化して
近づいたほうがいいからね。
but it's probably best to approach
by transforming into Sasori.
もし サソリが
天地橋に現れなければ➡
If Sasori doesn't show up
at the Tenchi Bridge,
相手も現れないかもしれない。
then the spy might not, either...
There's a distinct possibility.
その可能性は十分にある。
それじゃあ 意味ねえってばよ。
Then there'd be no point.
スパイは 相当のリスクを伴なう
行為だからね。
Being a spy is a very risky act, after all.
相手も かなり慎重になってる
ってことさ。
Which means the spy is probably
being quite cautious.
それじゃあ サソリには
ヤマト隊長が変化すんのか。
Then are you going to transform
into Sasori, Captain Yamato?
そうなるだろうね。
I'll probably have to.
サソリは 常に このヒルコという傀儡を
まとっていたそうだからね。
It seems he always remained
hidden inside this Hiruko puppet.
木遁忍術を使えるボクが
適任だろう。
So I'm probably the right one for this
since I can use the Wood Style Ninjutsu.
(サクラ)そうですね。
You're right.
And also, assuming this turns out
to be an Akatsuki trap...
それに 万が一
暁の罠という場合も想定して➡
ボクが まず １人で近づく。
I'll approach him alone at first.
((サソリ : 草隠れの里にある
天地橋に➡
At midday in ten days,
go to the Tenchi Bridge
10日後の真昼に行け。
located in the Village Hidden
in the Grass!
どういうこと？
What do you mean?
大蛇丸の部下に
オレのスパイがいる。
I've got a spy working as one
of Orochimaru's subordinates...
I was supposed to rendezvous...
with him...there...
(そこで ソイツと
落ち合う… ことに… なってる))
死に際の あの言い方。
The way he talked being near death...
たぶん ウソじゃないと思うけど…。
I don't think he was lying...
(サクラ)砂の里にも 由良っていう
暁のスパイがいたのは確かだし。
And there was indeed a spy
called Yura in the Sand Village...
(ヤマト)あくまでも
万が一を想定してのことだ。
This is just assuming
something goes wrong.
キミたちは ボクの指示があるまで
待機しててくれ。
You guys stand by until
I give you instructions.
Either way, there's no doubting...
(サイ)どちらにしても そのスパイ…。
相当のやり手に
間違いないでしょうね。
that spy is probably
considerably powerful.
…やってやるってばよ！
Let's do this!
さて ここからが本題だ。
Now then...
Now for the main issue...
今回の任務を
もう少し 具体的に言うとだね➡
Let me explain the mission in
a little more detail.
目標は あくまでも
逮捕であって➡
Our goal is just to arrest the target.
ターゲットを 死傷させてはならない。
We must not let him die,
even if we end up having to fight.
もし 戦闘になったとしてもだ。
殺してしまえば
大切な情報源が➡
We'll lose an important source of
information if the target is killed.
失われることになるからね。
そして この手の任務は➡
And a mission like this is more difficult
than just killing an enemy.
敵を倒すより 困難だ。
デリケートな任務だけに
まずは ボクが突入役だ。
As this is a delicate mission,
I will make the first move.
そして キミたちは支援役。
And you guys will be my back-up...
作戦は 簡単。
第一 ボクが ターゲットを拘束する。
The strategy is simple.
First, I restrain the target.
第二 もし ボクが
ターゲットの拘束をし損ね➡
Second, if I should fail
to restrain the target
and this turns into a battle,
戦闘になった場合。
キミたちも 戦闘行動に移行しろ。
you guys shift to battle formation.
I will give you a signal when
I want you to do this.
そのタイミングは ボクが合図する。
そして 第二の場合においては➡
And in the event of the second case,
you are to operate with
the Buddy System.
常に バディシステムで行動する。
ん？ バ… バディ シ システム？
B-Buddy System?
(ヤマト)１人が動くときは
相棒が 必ず援護する。
When one person takes action,
a partner always backs you up.
相互支援が 原則だ。
知ってるだろう？
Reciprocal back-up is
a fundamental rule.
You know about this, don't you?
Oh, yeah! That, huh?
ん… あぁ
あれね あれ！
あ… アハハ…。
しっかりしてよね。
Get it together, will you?
Now I'm going to determine
the Buddy Teams.
(ヤマト)で そのバディチームを
今決めておく。
まずは ボクと サクラのチーム。
First, Sakura and I will be one team!
それに ナルトと サイのチームだ。
And...
the other team will be...
Naruto and Sai!
《オレが… コイツと？》
Me...?
with him...?
You jerk! Don't you know
what the word comrade is?
やぁ みんな 今日はボクが➡
忍五大国について
説明するよ。
Of course! I could explain it
to you if you like.
忍五大国とは➡
強大な隠れ里を有する
五つの国➡
つまり
我らが火の国 木ノ葉隠れの里。
同盟国の風の国 砂隠れの里。
それに 土の国 岩隠れの里。
雷の国 雲隠れの里。
水の国 霧隠れの里の➡
五つをさす言葉だ。
この五大国の里の長だけに
許された➡
最強の忍の称号が 影。
五人の影を合わせて➡
五影とよぶんだ。
それじゃあ 問題を出すよ。
(ヤマト)正解は ご覧のとおり。
みんな できたかな？
できなかった人は…➡
ちゃんと復習するようにね。